(I never expected) all of you to be here present for the puja.
我从未期望你们全都能出席这个崇拜
I don't know how you all have managed to come.
我不知道你们是怎样设法来到的
Otherwise, it's a very important day today for all of us
不管如何对我们所有人来说 今天是一个非常重要的日子
because you know
因为你们都知道基督是怎样死的
Wonderful the way He said
祂却以很非凡的方式
about you people.
谈论你们大家
He asked for forgiveness from God.
祂请求神宽恕所有人
What we have to learn from His life is
我们要从祂的生命中学习的是
the way He knew how to forgive all of us.
祂懂得怎样去宽恕 宽恕所有人
We have to also forgive people.
我们要宽恕人们
That seems to be very difficult for people to forgive.
对于人们来说去宽恕似乎是非常困难的
And if they are angry, they are angry,
而如果你是愤怒的 那么你不能宽恕
Sahaja yogis must forgive, it's very important
作为霎哈嘉瑜伽士你必须去宽恕 那是非常重要的
because that is the power you have got from Christ: to forgive.
因为那正是你从基督处获得的力量
Human beings make mistakes; that is a part of their life.
人类会犯错 那是他们生命的一部分
But at the same time, as sahaja yogis you must remember that you have to forgive.
但同时作为霎哈嘉瑜伽士 你一定要明白你要去宽恕
That is much more important than getting angry.
这是比变得愤怒重要的多的
So to forgive people for doing something wrong according to you
所以去宽恕那些做了某些错事的人
or according to God, you have to forgive.
对你或对神 你要去宽恕
And you will be surprised that the forgiveness
并且你会惊奇的发现宽恕
is such a great, satisfying quality.
是那样伟大而美好的品格
If you can forgive people,
如果你可以宽恕
you will become extremely pure
你们将变得非常的纯洁
because the dirt or the anger that is within us goes out.
因为你原本的污点和愤怒都消失了
So to forgive is the biggest blessings human beings have.
所以宽恕是人类所拥有的最大的祝福
Even Christ said the same thing
甚至基督也说着同样的
that, "Forgive them because they don't know what they are doing."
我宽恕他们 因为他们不知道他们正在做什么
So if Christ had to say, so what about you?
那么如果基督曾这样说 何况你们呢
We are ordinary human beings and if we have done mistakes,
我们都是普通人 如果我们犯了错
people can get angry and upset with you.
人们可以生气并使你不安
But the best thing for you is to forgive.
但对你们 最好的事情却是去宽恕
Forgive for doing something that should not have been done.
宽恕那些做了不应该做的事情的人
This was the biggest quality of Christ: that He knew how to forgive.
这就是基督最伟大的品格 祂懂得怎样去宽恕
And He forgave people who had made horrible mistakes.
祂宽恕曾经犯下可怕的过错的人们
Still He forgave them because He loved them.
祂宽恕他们 因为祂爱他们
And that is what you should also forgive.
这就是为什么你也要宽恕
Today is a special day for that - special day for forgiveness.
今天是一个特别的日子 一个宽恕的日子
And that is why I said, whatever you may think,
这就是为什么我说不管你怎样想
it's very late, but we'll have a meeting because I didn't want to miss the time.
时间很晚了 我们能汇聚一堂是非常好的 因为我不想错过这个时机
Forgiveness comes by people who are very generous, who are good-hearted.
宽恕来自于宽厚的人 他们心地善良
You, everybody makes mistakes and so we can also make mistakes.
你知道 每个人都犯错 我们也会犯错
But that means we have a right to forgive
但这意味着我们拥有宽恕的权利
and we have a heart to forgive.
一颗宽恕的心
If you don't have, then we are not sahaja yogis.
如果你没有 你就不是一个霎哈嘉瑜伽士
We must learn to forgive and forgive without any remarks behind it.
你必须学习宽恕 毫无保留地宽恕
Today is a very special day because that's what Christ did.
今天是一个非常特殊的日子 因为基督正是那样做的
He was one of the most powerful deities or gods as we may say, most powerful.
可以这样说 祂是最有力量的神祈 或天神之一 最具能量的
He could do anything; He could punish them, all of them, for misbehaving.
祂可以做任何事情 祂可以惩罚他们 他们所有人 为那错误行径
But what did He say? He said, "I forgive"
但祂说过什么 祂说 我宽恕
and He asked God also to forgive.
并且祂请求上帝也宽恕
So whatever may be your powers,
所以不管你拥有怎样的力量
whatever you might have achieved in your life,
你的生活中成就了什么
whatever position you might be occupying,
拥有怎样的地位
but you must learn the way to forgive.
但你必须学习宽恕
Otherwise you are nowhere near Christ.
否则你不能接近基督
You must learn to forgive; that's a very great quality
你必须去宽恕 那是一种如此伟大的品格
if you can forgive, all the time forgive.
如果你能宽恕 始终宽恕
And that's why today I wanted to meet you all, so I did.
这就是今天我想要见到你们大家的原因
I wanted to meet you all and tell you
我希望见到你们并告诉你们
that today is a day to forgive.
今天是去宽恕的日子
That doesn't mean you sit down and think, oh, how many people you have to forgive.
这并不是说让你坐下来 并思考有多少人你要去宽恕
That would be absurd.
那是荒谬的
But something that haunts your mind
但有些事情萦绕在你脑中
and you think you all been troubled and you have been put to trouble.
你感到苦恼 陷入混乱中
Then just think that you don't know how many powers you have
有意思的是你不明白你拥有多少力量
and you can't even forgive. When you have got all these powers;
你甚至不能宽恕 你拥有所有的力量
the greatest power you have got is to forgive.
而最大的力量是去宽恕
And today is the day for forgiving,
今天是宽恕的日子
forgiving people whom you think they have done wrong to you,
宽恕那些你认为对你做下错事的人
or they have been unkind to you. Please try to remember
或对你不很友爱的人
Just forgive them. Then you have punished them.
只是宽恕 那么你也因此得到宽恕
If you forgive them from your heart, then you have punished them.
如果你发自内心宽恕他们 你就已经惩罚了他们
You have given them back, whatever they wanted, they deserved.
你已经给回了他们希望的或应得的
So this is not a very difficult thing, to forgive,
所以 去宽恕这不是一件非常难的事情
but people think it's very difficult to forgive
但人们觉得宽恕是非常困难的
because they have certain great understandings about themselves.
因为他们觉得自己了不起
And then they think how can they forgive?
他们想 他们怎能去宽恕
I don't know what things upset you, anything can upset you.
我不知道什么使你不安 任何事情都能使你不安
After all, you are all realized souls, you have got your second birth
毕竟 你们都是已获自觉的灵 你已经获得重生
and you are special people. So you should have a special quality.
是特别的人类 所以你应该具有不一般的品格
And the special quality is to forgive, to forgive.
去宽恕的特别品格 去宽恕
Not to go on remembering on what things you should be angry and you should be upset.
不要继续记得你为什么愤怒 为什么不安
But just to remember what things you have to forgive. Just forgive.
只需记得有什么要去宽恕 只是宽恕
For what?
为了什么呢
Is a practical thing, most practical.
它是一个实际的事情 最实在的
Supposing somebody slaps me, alright.
设想某人用掌掴我 好吧
If somebody slaps me, what should I do?
如果有人用掌掴我 我应如何
I should slap him back? No.
我掴回他 不是
Then why should I ask him, "Why did you slap me?" No.
或我应问他 你为什么打我 不是
Then I should think he must be stupid fool to do like that?
或我应想他一定是个愚蠢的家伙才这样做
Even that won't help. On the contrary, if you can just forgive,
这没有用 相反 你可以只是宽恕
forgive that person who has done something wrong...
宽恕那个犯错的人
For you it is important that you must forgive because has no effect.
对你来说你宽恕是重要的 因为其它的都没有用
Once you forgive, it will have more effect on you, your goodness, your righteousness.
当你懂得宽恕 这对你的善行 你的美德都有更好的影响
But I think human beings find it difficult to forgive normally. Normally.
但我想人类发现去宽恕是困难的 通常如此 通常如此
But you are all realized souls; you are not only human beings.
但你们是已获自觉的灵 你们不仅是人类
That's why I'm requesting you that remember you have a power to forgive.
这也是为什么我正要求你记住 你拥有去宽恕的力量
To forgive everyone who hurts you,
宽恕每一个人 伤害你的人
who tortures you, who troubles you. How far can he go?
折磨你的人 麻烦你的人 你们能走多远
Just think of forgiving him and you'll be amazed, he will change.
只是想着宽恕他 你将感到惊奇 他会改变
He will change and you will also enjoy yourself.
他将改变而你也将享受自己
It's a difficult thing for people to understand, but just try.
理解这些对人们是困难的 但请只是试试
Just try what I'm saying. If somebody does any harm to you,
只是尝试我正在说的 如果某人伤害了你
just forgive that person and see the reaction,
只是宽恕那个人 并看看反应
reaction in that person and in yourself. What happens?
在那人和在你自己身上的反应 看会发生什么
But if you want to carry the burden of his anger or of stupidity, whatever it is,
但如果你想要在愤怒 愚蠢 或什么的重负之中
then you are unnecessarily loaded with useless things.
你将毫无必要的令自己装载着无用的东西
We should not waste our energy on deciding
我们不应浪费我们的精力 来决定什么是错的
what's wrong, what did he do and what you should do to him, that we should not.
他做了什么 你应对他做什么 我们不应那样
Just leave him alone and you just forgive. Say that, "I forgive."
只需别管他 并且你宽恕 说 我宽恕
Look at Christ. Such a powerful person; such a powerful god!
看看基督 如此有力量的人 如此有力量的神
And when He was crucified,
当祂被钉死十字架上
how He asked for forgiveness for them.
祂怎样请求宽恕他们
Why did He do it? Because that has power.
为什么祂这样做 因为那就是力量
Saying, "I forgive", it's very powerful.
说 我宽恕 是非常有力量的
You don't lose your power, but on the contrary,
你不要失去这力量 而是相反
you go higher in your power.
你在这力量上走的更高
You go higher in your personality.
在你的人格上走的更高
Just forgive. As simple as that.
只是宽恕 就这么简单
To say that, "I forgive," just like that.
说 我宽恕 就象这样
That's how I do because people have their own whims
那正是我怎样做 因为人们有他们自己的方式
and they do whatever they like, but I don't get angry on that point.
他们做他们喜欢的 但我不为那感到生气
And I'm not upset on that point, neither I am concerned.
我既不对那感到不安 我也不关心
I just say, "I forgive," that's all.
我只是说 我宽恕 这是全部
And you'll be amazed, within myself, it so helps so much, really very helpful.
你会惊奇的发现 我自己内在 它帮助很大 真的非常有帮助
So this is a very big quality for which today is a special day.
对今天这个特殊的日子 这是一个非常好的品格
On the cross Christ said that, "Oh God, forgive them because they don't know
在十字架上 基督说 我希望上帝宽恕他们 因为他们不知道
what they are doing." On the cross where He was dying He said this,
他们正在做什么 在十字架上 祂快要死了 祂这样说
and what we have to learn is to forgive,
我们要学会去宽恕
for our sake, not for others. This helps us. If we forgive,
为了我们自己的缘故 不是为了其它人 这会帮助我们 如果我们宽恕
this will help us very much within ourselves.
这在我们自己内里帮助非常大
This is the message for today and permanently. Permanently.
这是今天的启示 也是永远的 恒久不变的
Always, if you are angry with anyone, just say, "I forgive."
如果你对任何人感到生气 只要说 我宽恕
If you find somebody hurting you or troubling you or torturing you,
如果你发现某人麻烦你 伤害你或折磨你
how you will work on it? Just forgive, just forgive. This is the only way.
不管他们犯什么错 只是宽恕 只是宽恕 这是唯一的方法
Today that's why is very important day for us and I'm so very happy
今天对我们是非常重要的日子
Thank you.
谢谢你们